## **Mashuk Sadman**

mashuksadman@gmail.com +88 01726 634 711

#### **Personal Statement**

I have been working with React and native android application development for last 6-7 years and have a good experience on React JS, Redux, Redux-Saga, Reflux, JavaScript [ES7], databases, different libraries etc. as well as I have solved over 650 uva problems which are mainly related to math, algorithm, graph, dynamic programming, problem solving paradigms and data structure.

## **Objectives**

Seeking a position in a company where I can apply my software engineering experience specially on React JS & logic related problems and contribute to the development process both as an individual and a good team player.

#### **Skills**

Technology: React Js, Redux, Redux-Saga, Reflux, JavaScript [ES7]

API: FabricJs, Google, Algolia, Facebook, Twitter, Github, Firebase, Auth0, etc.

**IDE:** Android Studio

**DBMS:** MySQL, Sqlite, Firebase, Firestore

**Automation Tools**: Webpack

Versioning: Git

Project Management: Scrum

#### **Portfolio**

<u>Isomorphic - React Redux Admin Dashboard (Redq Inc.):</u> A react-redux powered single page admin dashboard. Used progressive web application pattern, highly optimized for react application.

Reactive Pro - Redg Inc (Redg Inc.): Make searching easy for your customers. Advanced search, filter & grid plugin, powered by react-redux. It can search through post, product, custom post types, taxonomies, metadata and term metas. It has built in with geo box and location searching facility.

<u>Mate - React Redux Material Admin Dashboard (Redq Inc.):</u> A react-redux powered single page material admin dashboard. Used progressive web application pattern, highly optimized for react application.

<u>Prohoree (TechCareBD):</u> Current condition & information of Vehicles instantly featuring Real time tracking, Pin point location, Latitude & Longitude, Start Stop Report, Travel History, Speed Report etc.

<u>Pathashala (TechCareBD):</u> A video tube for students where everyone can watch video tutorials. OnnoRokom Pathshala offers you a different approach of learning.

Maa o shishu (10th at EATL Prothom-Alo app contest 2013): Maa o shishu has the moto to help pregnant mother & their new born child. It keeps almost all the technological help that a smart phone can provide.

**4K Wallpaper (Zert Interactive):** Wallpaper collection installed over 100k. This app is packed with some awesome backgrounds. It has been installed over 100,000.

<u>CricScore (Zert Interactive):</u> Cricket score related live wallpaper. You can set the match score as live wallpaper on your home screen.

<u>Hepatitis (Zert Interactive):</u> Hepatitis consciousness app in BANGLA. Its Awareness app.

<u>Mustache Booth (Zert Interactive):</u> This app is a simple entertainment app that allows to put a mustache, beard and funny comments on anyone or anything.

**UVA Solution:** Over 650 problems solved in different categories mostly related to math, data structure and algorithm.

## **Work Experience**

## **Software Engineer | RedQ Inc.**

July, 2016 - Present

I mainly develop react based apps here. I worked with various modules, restful APIs, dashboard and wordpress plugins. I have to test and solve bugs in their functioning. I collaborated with designers to meet customers' expectations and optimized website usability. We have to maintain the team workflow to complete programming and development tasks of different difficulty levels.

#### **Senior Android developer | Zert Interactive**

January, 2016 - June, 2016

Zert Interactive mainly deals with android and IOS apps. Among android apps I have worked over 80 projects including live wallpapers, live score streaming, custom ui generator and so on.

#### **Assistant Software Engineer | System Resources Ltd.**

March, 2015 - December, 2015

System Resources Limited (SRL) offer services for developing business application software & app, database management, IT audit and project management software & app etc. I developed android apps here.

#### Android developer | TechCare Ltd.

2012 - 2014

A start up for ui/ux design, mobile app development and web app development. I worked as ux developer and android apps development.

# **Education**

Exam Title	Institute	Session	Result
B.Sc. in Computer	Rajshahi University of	2010-2014	3.28 out of 4.00
Science & Engineering	Engineering & Technology		
HSC	Cantonment public School	2009	5.00 out of 5.00
	& College, Rangpur		
SSC	Cantonment public School	2007	5.00 out of 5.00
	& College, Rangpur		

## **Awards**

- 1st position CSE Fest Inter University Programming Contest 2012, RUET
- 2nd position CSE Inter Programming Contest 2014, RUET
- > 6th position Code Warriors challenge, 2014
- > 10th position EATL Prothom-Alo app contest 2013
- > Participating in ACM ICPC 3 times, 2010-12
- Excellence Performance Award 2014, RUET
- > UVA online-judge problems solved 650, ranked 514

## **External Links**

**Online CV**: https://halumz.github.io **Github**: https://github.com/halumz

**Linkedin**: www.linkedin.com/in/mashuksadman **UVA**: http://uhunt.onlinejudge.org/id/71527

Hackerrank: https://www.hackerrank.com/mashuksadman